glencoe.com 2016-11-25

# Privacy Center

## Customer Data Privacy Notice

### Introduction

Please note that this notice applies to individuals who visit our commercial web sites or otherwise interact with us as customers or potential employees via our web sites, social media, or at events. 

Our commercial web sites, such as mheonline.com, mhprofessional.com, or mheducation.com, are not intended for use by minors below the age of 13. Privacy information for users of our digital learning systems, including those under the age of 13, can be found by following the appropriate links to the left (Educators, Students, and Parents). 

This notice does not cover other organizations' web sites that may be accessible via links on our web sites. These sites have their own privacy policies and we encourage you to read them. 

McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization. We follow all privacy laws and regulations that are applicable to our company and our services in the areas where we do business. You agree that by accessing our web sites or otherwise providing your personal information to McGraw-Hill Education, you accept this notice. It is your responsibility to fully read through this notice. If you do not agree to this notice, you may not access our web sites or otherwise provide your personal information to McGraw-Hill Education. 

Revisions to this Privacy Notice will be posted at this location. Material changes may also be posted to the homepage of our website. 

Please contact our Chief Privacy Officer with any questions or concerns: 

**Email:** [privacy@mheducation.com](mailto:privacy@mheducation.com)

**Postal Address:**   
Chief Privacy Officer   
McGraw-Hill Education   
2 Penn Plaza, 20th Floor   
New York, NY 10121 

### Privacy Notice

**_What is Personally Identifiable Information (PII)?_**

Personally Identifiable Information, or PII, is information that can identify you, or when combined with other information can be used to identify you. Depending on the service or transaction, the PII that MHE collects on customers may contain the following categories: 

  1. First name, last name, and/or initials
  2. Personal contact information and/or contact information at your place of business such as email address, phone numbers, or postal address
  3. Education and professional details such as school(s) or courses attended
  4. Payment card industry data such as credit card number, billing address

* * *

**_What PII do we collect and how do we use it?_**

 ** _We collect PII, such as contact information, education details, or payment information, in order to provide you with the product and/or service requested._**

We, or our service providers on our behalf, may collect PII and other information if you access and/or submit PII on one of our web sites or interact with us at an event. You are not required to provide PII, however in order to use certain services, we must collect PII in order for that service to function properly or to provide you with additional information, if requested. In general, we collect PII if it is necessary to provide, maintain, and improve the requested service, such as McGraw-Hill Education web sites or process transactions, such as information requests or purchases. It is your responsibility to ensure the integrity of the data you provide to us. You may contact customer service to update your PII. 

We limit the use, collection, and disclosure of your PII to deliver the service or information requested by you. We do not collect, use, or disclose PII that is not reasonably related to the purposes described within this notice. Your information may be combined in an aggregate and de-identified manner in order to maintain and/or improve our services. 

Depending on the service or transaction, the PII we collect may include information from the following categories: 

  1. Name, initials or white page information
    1. On our consumer web sites, we generally only collect your name, initials or contact information when you create an account or purchase a product on our online store. We may also collect your email address. We may also collect this information if you connect with us via your social media account as an existing or potential customer, or if you are interested in a career at McGraw-Hill Education.
  2. Education & and professional information
    1. If you are interested in a career with us, we may collect additional education and professional information online, primarily in the form of an online form or resume. We use this information to evaluate candidates, conduct interviews and initiate the hiring process.
  3. Payment card industry data such as credit card number, billing address, etc.
    1. If you make an online purchase from us, in addition to your name, we may need to collect additional payment information, which includes billing and shipping addresses and credit card data in order to process your transaction.

* * *

**_What other information do we collect?_**

 ** _We may also collect computer metadata and content to provide, improve, and maintain our products and services._**

When you visit and make transactions on our web sites, we collect information without you having to enter it through the use of cookies, web beacons or other tracking mechanisms. This includes information about your experience such as your IP address, operating systems, pages viewed, and time spent. Information may also be collected automatically from you through the use of third party cookies, web beacons, and tracking mechanisms. This information is used to enable the functions of the site, as well as customize, maintain, and improve our web sites. You may disable cookies via your browser or third party mechanisms. However, some features of our services may not functional properly without them. Third party cookies which may be used include: 

  * AddThis
  * Adobe Test & Target
  * DoubleClick
  * Eloqua
  * Google: Various including AdWord Conversion, Analytics, Tag Manager, etc.
  * LivePerson
  * Marketo
  * Omniture

If you access our web sites from the European Union, you will be presented with an additional notification regarding cookies and will be provided with an opportunity to approve the use of cookies. 

You can change your Web browser's Internet preferences to disable or delete cookies, although that may affect certain functions on this site. To learn how to manage your cookies, please follow the instructions from your specific browser, or follow the links below: 

If you wish to opt out of the use of data collected on our site to send you targeted advertising during your visits to other websites, go to [http://www.aboutads.info/choices.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). 

* * *

**_Do we use your PII to market to you?_**

 ** _We may market to you as a customer, depending on your location, however you always have the option to change your marketing preferences._**

Depending on your location, we may use your PII to provide you with materials that we believe are of interest. In some locations, such as the European Union, we will only market to you if you request such materials. In all instances, you may choose to change these preferences at any time by contacting our [customer service](http://www.mheducation.com/contact.html) or by sending an email to [McGraw-Hill Education's local privacy official](http://www.mheducation.com/privacy/customer-privacy-contacts.html). McGraw-Hill Education will not share your PII with third parties for marketing purposes unless the organization is acting on our behalf and is contractually bound to only use your PII for those purposes. Please note, whatever preferences you select for marketing, you may still receive some transactional emails related to the services or products you purchase or use. 

* * *

**_When do we share your PII with third parties?_**

 ** _In general, we only share your PII in order to provide, maintain, or improve our products or services, or respond to legal requests._**

  1. Co-branded/Other Web Sites and Features – We may share your PII with third-party business partners for the purpose of providing the Service to you. Those business partners will be given limited access to the PII that is reasonably necessary to deliver the Service, and we will require that such third parties follow the same privacy and security practices as McGraw-Hill Education.
  2. Business Transfer – In the event of a sale, merger or acquisition, we may transfer your PII to a separate entity. This entity will be responsible for ensuring that your PII is used only for authorized purposes and by authorized persons in a manner consistent with the choices customers and prospects have made under this Policy, and that security, integrity and privacy of the information is maintained.
  3. Agents/Service providers – Sometimes we hire other companies to perform certain business-related functions for us. In certain instances, we provide these companies with access to your PII in order for them to perform their functions. However, we limit that access to only information required to perform their specific function, and we contractually require that these organizations follow the same privacy and security requirements.
  4. Contests and Promotions – If you participate in a contest or promotion with McGraw-Hill Education, we may use your information to provide, maintain, or improve our services, as well as, where permitted, contact you regarding materials in which you may be interested.
  5. Affiliates – McGraw-Hill Education is a global corporation that consists of multiple organizations. In some instances, we may share your PII between organizations within McGraw-Hill Education to provide, maintain, and improve our products and services.
  6. Law Enforcement – In the event that McGraw-Hill Education receives a legal demand for customer data from a law enforcement agency that request will only be honored if:
    1. The request complies with all laws and clearly establishes the legal need for disclosure.
    2. The request is related to a specific investigation and specific user accounts are implicated in that investigation.
    3. Whenever legally permissible, users shall receive notice that their information is being requested.

* * *

**_What privacy controls and choices do we offer you?_**

 ** _You may review and correct your PII by contacting customer service._**

  1. Reviewing & correcting your information – We strive to ensure that information we have about you is accurate and current. If you want to review the PII you have provided to us, or believe that the information we have about you is inaccurate, you should contact our [customer service](http://www.mheducation.com/contact.html) to review or update your PII.
  2. Choice – With limited exceptions, you may choose to change how we use your PII at any time by contacting [customer service](http://www.mheducation.com/contact.html). However, if the PII is required to provide you with the service or process a transaction, you may not be able to opt-out without canceling the transaction or service.

* * *

**_How do we protect your PII?_**

 ** _Our IT security team has established reasonable security measures to protect your PII_**

We use reasonable security measures to protect your PII from unauthorized access and use. 

* * *

**_Can you delete your PII?_**

 ** _You may request, via[customer service](http://www.mheducation.com/contact.html), that we delete your PII, however it may limit your abilities to use our products or services._**

At your request, in some instances, we may delete or de-identify your information. However, you should be aware that doing this may limit your use of our services. For example, if you request the deletion of your account within an ecommerce portal, you may be required to re-enter this information should you wish to make another purchase. 

* * *

**_When do we store, transfer or process PII internationally?_**

 ** _McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization based in the U.S. Depending on your location, we may transfer and store your PII for processing in the U.S._**

McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization headquartered in the United States. Depending on your location and the product or service, your information may be stored and processed within secure data centers in the U.S., where U.S. law applies. If your data is stored locally, then your local laws prevail. 

We recognize and acknowledge current data protection laws in the European Union, Switzerland, and around the world. We follow the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Framework administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at http://www.export.gov/safeharbor. 

Any questions or complaints regarding this Policy or the collection, use, disclosure, or transfer of Personal Data covered by this Policy should be directed to [privacy@mheducation.com](mailto:privacy@mheducation.com). 

In the event your complaint cannot be resolved, you may contact the appropriate DPA or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner. The contact information for the EU DPAs is available at http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/index_en.htm. The contact information for the Commissioner is available at <http://www.edoeb.admin.ch/kontakt/index.html?lang=en>.

## Educator Data Privacy Notice

### Introduction

The below privacy information applies to educators who use our digital learning systems. We are happy to provide this information, however your educational institution will have full details and is ultimately responsible for the privacy of your personal information. Should you have any detailed questions or concerns about the privacy practices in place for your information, please contact the appropriate representative at your institution. 

This policy does not cover other organizations' sites that may be accessible via links on our sites. These sites have their own privacy policies and we encourage you to read them. 

McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization. We follow all privacy laws and regulations in the areas where we do business. Revisions to these privacy practices will be posted at this location; however, we will also notify your educational institution directly should there be material changes. 

### Privacy Practices

**_What is Personally Identifiable Information (PII)?_**

 ** _Personally Identifiable Information, or PII, is information that can identify you, or when combined with other information can be used to identify you._**

Personally Identifiable Information, or PII, is information that can identify you, or when combined with other information can be used to identify you. Depending on the service or transaction, the PII that MHE collects on customers may contain the following categories of information: 

  1. Name and initials
  2. Personal contact information and/or contact information at your place of business such as email address, phone numbers, or postal address
  3. Education and professional details such as school(s) or courses attended

* * *

**_What PII do we collect and how do we use it?_**

 ** _We collect PII, such as contact information and education details, in order to provide you with the product and/or service requested._** We limit the use, collection, and disclosure of your PII to the minimum necessary to deliver the digital learning system and provide customer service. We do not collect, use, or disclose PII that is not reasonably related to a legitimate business purpose necessary to serve you. Your information may be combined in an aggregate and de-identified manner in order to maintain and/or improve our digital learning systems, or provide customer service. 

Depending on the product, the PII we collect may include information from the following categories: 

  1. Name, initials, and/or personal or business related contact information
    1. For our digital learning systems, we generally only collect your name/initials and contact information when you create an account. However, we may collect additional PII, or confirm existing PII if you contact customer service with an issue or question. Please note that in some instances, we receive PII from third parties who provide single-sign on functions via Learning Management Systems or related tools. Please contact your educational institution for further details.
  2. Education & professional information 
    1. For some digital learning systems, we may collect PII related to your position as an educator. This includes the state, district, name of school, courses, etc. This PII is used to provide you with access and use of the digital learning system, as well as maintain and improve our digital learning systems.

* * *

**_What other information do we collect?_**

 ** _We may also collect computer metadata and content to provide, improve, and maintain our products and services._**

When you use our digital learning systems, we collect information without you having to enter it through the use of cookies, web beacons or other tracking mechanisms. This includes information about your experience such as your IP address, operating systems, pages viewed, and time spent. This information is also used to enable the functions of the digital learning system, as well as customize, maintain, and improve our digital learning systems. You may disable cookies via your browser or third party mechanisms. However, some features of our digital learning systems may not functional properly without them. Third party cookies that may be used include: 

  * Disqus
  * Google Analytics
  * Marketo
  * Pingdom
  * Webtrends

Please note, if applicable, we may combine information that you or your students enter into our digital learning systems with PII that we may maintain on you as a customer. We combine this PII to provide you with better customer service and to tailor marketing to areas that are more appropriate for you. As noted in our Customer Privacy Notice, you are always able to opt-out of receiving these communications. 

If you access our web sites from the European Union, you will be presented with an additional notification regarding cookies and will be provided with an opportunity to approve the use of cookies. 

You can change your Web browser's Internet preferences to disable or delete cookies, although that may affect certain functions on this site. To learn how to manage your cookies, please follow the instructions from your specific browser, or follow the links below: 

If you wish to opt out of the use of data collected on our site to send you targeted advertising during your visits to other websites, go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. 

* * *

**_Do we use your PII to market to you?_**

 ** _We may market to you as a customer, depending on your location, however you always have the option to change your marketing preferences._**

Depending on your location, we may use your PII to provide you with materials that we believe are of interest. In some locations, such as the European Union, we will only market to you if you request such materials. In all instances, you may choose to change these preferences at any time by contacting our [customer service](http://www.mheducation.com/contact.html) or by [sending an email](http://www.mheducation.com/privacy/customer-privacy-contacts.html) to McGraw-Hill Education's local privacy official. McGraw-Hill Education will not share your PII with third parties for marketing purposes unless the organization is acting on our behalf and is contractually bound to only use your PII for those purposes. Please note, whatever preferences you select for marketing, you may still receive some transactional emails related to the services or products you use. 

* * *

**_When do we share your PII with third parties?_**

 ** _In general, we only share your PII in order to provide, maintain, or improve our products or services, or respond to legal requests._**

  1. Co-branded/Other Web Sites and Features – We may share your PII with third-party business partners for the purpose of providing the digital learning system to you. Those business partners will be given limited access to PII that is reasonably necessary to deliver the digital learning system, and we will require that such third parties follow the same privacy and security standards.
  2. Business Transfer – In the event of a sale, merger or acquisition, we may transfer your PII to a separate entity. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to help ensure that your PII is used only for authorized purposes and by authorized persons in a manner consistent with the choices customers and prospects have made under this Policy, and that security, integrity and privacy of your PII is maintained.
  3. Agents/Service providers – Sometimes we hire other companies to perform certain business-related functions for us. In certain instances, we provide these companies with access to your PII in order for them to perform their functions. However, we limit that access to only information required to perform their specific function. We also require these companies to follow these same privacy and security standards.
  4. Contests and Promotions - If you participate in a contest or promotion with McGraw-Hill Education, we may use your information to provide, maintain, or improve our services, as well as, where permitted, contact you regarding materials in which you may be interested.
  5. Affiliates – McGraw-Hill Education is a global corporation that consists of multiple organizations. In some instances, we may share your PII between organizations within McGraw-Hill Education to provide, maintain, and improve our products and services.
  6. Customers – As we are a service provider to your school, we may share your date with approved individuals at your school, such as administrators
  7. Law Enforcement – In the event that McGraw-Hill Education receives a legal demand for PII from a law enforcement agency, the request will only be honored if:
    1. The request complies with all laws and clearly establishes the legal need for disclosure.
    2. The request is related to a specific investigation and specific user accounts are implicated in that investigation.
    3. Whenever legally permissible, users shall receive notice that their information is being requested.

* * *

**_What privacy controls and choices do we offer you?_**

 ** _You may contact customer service to review or correct your PII._**

  1. Reviewing & correcting your information – We strive to ensure that the PII we have about you is accurate and current. However, since McGraw-Hill Education is a service provider to your school, please contact the appropriate contact at your school if you want to review your account information, or believe that the PII we have about you is inaccurate.
  2. Consent – As noted above, your educational institution is ultimately responsible for the privacy of your PII. MHE obtains consent from your institution to collect, process, and store your PII. If you have any questions regarding the collection and use of your PII, please contact the appropriate individual at your educational institution

* * *

**_How do we protect your PII?_**

 ** _Our IT security team has established reasonable security measures to protect your PII._**

We use reasonable security measures to protect your PII from unauthorized access and use. 

* * *

**_Can you delete your PII?_**

 ** _You may request that we delete your PII through your school, however you should be aware this may limit your ability to use our products or services._**

At the request of your educational institution, in some instances, we may delete or de-identify your PII. However, you should be aware that doing this may limit your use of our products. For example, if we receive a request to delete your account within a digital learning system, you may no longer be able to log into that digital learning system. 

* * *

**_When do we store, transfer or process PII internationally?_**

 ** _McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization based in the U.S. Depending on your location, we may transfer and store your PII for processing in the U.S._**

McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization headquartered in the United States. Depending on your location and the product or service, your information may be stored and processed within secure data centers in the U.S., where U.S. law applies. If your data is stored locally, then your local laws prevail. 

We recognize and acknowledge current data protection laws in the European Union, Switzerland, and around the world. We follow the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Framework administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at http://www.export.gov/safeharbor. 

Any questions or complaints regarding this Policy or the collection, use, disclosure, or transfer of Personal Data covered by this Policy should be directed to [privacy@mheducation.com](mailto:privacy@mheducation.com). 

In the event your complaint cannot be resolved, you may contact the appropriate DPA or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner. The contact information for the EU DPAs is available at http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/index_en.htm. The contact information for the Commissioner is available at <http://www.edoeb.admin.ch/kontakt/index.html?lang=en>.

## Parent Data Privacy Notice

### Introduction

Protecting privacy and maintaining the trust of our customers, their students, and parents has always been a key priority for us. To enhance learning, we need access to data, measurement, insight and other feedback that inform us about students' knowledge and skill levels and learning development. 

  * Our goal is to use data in the course of current learning activities to provide adaptive pathways of learning; not drive commerce.
  * We want to communicate with parents and schools about the educational benefit of using technology to create a personalized learning path based on past performance, and the need to use student information for educational purposes.
  * We want to build trust about the way we use personally identifiable student data for educational purposes.

And our commitment to privacy and innovation goes beyond compliance, it's part of our culture: 

  * We have implemented policies and procedures around these issues to support schools and institutions in their COPPA and FERPA compliance efforts.
  * In 2013, we appointed one of the education industry's first Chief Privacy Officers.
  * We've taken a leadership role with Future of Privacy Forum (FPF) and the Software and Information Industry Association (SIIA) in setting the agenda for self-regulatory goals for student privacy in the industry.
  * We have an internal Privacy Council comprised of senior leaders throughout our company insuring best practices across our business.
  * We do not support business models that create tolls and taxes on interoperability.
  * We conduct regular scans of all of our applications to prevent and detect any possible security breaches. We recognize that no system is 100% secure, but do everything we can to prevent and mitigate any impact of adverse events.

By increasing awareness and transparency, we hope to better understand the concerns and learn how to talk with each other about privacy, security, and confidentiality. 

Educational institutions are ultimately responsible for providing a full understanding of the privacy practices around how their students' personally identifiable information is collected, shared, and used. To obtain more detailed information about how data is collected, used, and shared by an educational institution, please contact the appropriate individual at that institution. 

* * *

**_What is personally identifiable information (PII)?_**

 ** _Personally Identifiable Information, or PII, is information that can identify you, or when combined with other information can be used to identify you._**

Personally identifiable information, or PII, is information that can be used to identify you, such as your name, address, or ID numbers. PII also includes information that can be combined to identify you, such as you date of birth and birthplace. Any information that is combined with PII, is also considered PII as long as it is linked to PII. For example, we couldn't identify you based on your grade level, however grade level is PII as long as it is connected to you. 

* * *

**_What PII do we collect and how do we use it?_**

 ** _We collect PII, such as contact information and education details, in order to provide, maintain and improve our products and services._**

We only collect the information we require to provide, maintain and improve the digital learning solution you and your child use. When you and/or your child register, or are registered within one of our digital learning solutions, we typically only collect your name, school, instructor, class, and login information. However, once you begin using one of our solutions, we collect your input to questions, technical specifications, and other information about how you use the solution. As mentioned above, we use this information to provide you and your child with the solution, as well as maintain and improve the solution. 

* * *

**_What other information do we collect?_**

 ** _We may also collect computer metadata and content to provide, improve, and maintain our products and services._**

When you use our digital learning systems, we collect information without you having to enter it through the use of cookies, web beacons or other tracking mechanisms. This includes information about your experience such as your IP address, operating systems, pages viewed, and time spent. This information is also used to enable the functions of the digital learning system, as well as customize, maintain, and improve our digital learning systems. You may disable cookies via your browser or third party mechanisms. However, some features of our digital learning systems may not functional properly without them. Third party cookies that may be used include Google Analytics and Webtrends. 

If you access our web sites from the European Union, you will be presented with an additional notification regarding cookies and will be provided with an opportunity to approve the use of cookies. 

You can change your Web browser's Internet preferences to disable or delete cookies, although that may affect certain functions on this site. To learn how to manage your cookies, please follow the instructions from your specific browser, or follow the links below: 

* * *

**_Do we use your PII to market to you?_**

 ** _We will not sell your PII or market to you using PII from our digital learning systems._**

We will not sell your or your child's PII to other organizations, nor will we send your child advertisements using the information we collect while you use the solution. In addition, we will not share this information with any third party unless they are assisting us with providing, maintaining or improving the solution. If we do share your information, we require that those organizations commit to the same levels of privacy and security that we do. 

* * *

**_When do we share your PII with third parties?_**

 ** _In general, we only share your PII in order to provide, maintain, or improve our products or services, or respond to legal requests._**

  1. Co-branded/Other Web Sites and Features – We may share your PII with third-party business partners for the purpose of providing the digital learning system to you. Those business partners will be given limited access to PII that is reasonably necessary to deliver the digital learning system, and we will require that such third parties follow the same privacy and security standards.
  2. Business Transfer – In the event of a sale, merger or acquisition, we may transfer your PII to a separate entity. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to help ensure that your PII is used only for authorized purposes and by authorized persons in a manner consistent with the choices customers and prospects have made under this Policy, and that security, integrity and privacy of your PII is maintained.
  3. Agents/Service providers – Sometimes we hire other companies to perform certain business-related functions for us. In certain instances, we provide these companies with access to your PII in order for them to perform their functions. However, we limit that access to only information required to perform their specific function. We also require these companies to follow these same privacy and security standards.
  4. Contests and Promotions – If you participate in a contest or promotion with McGraw-Hill Education, we may use your information to provide, maintain, or improve our services, as well as, where permitted, contact you regarding materials in which you may be interested.
  5. Affiliates – McGraw-Hill Education is a global corporation that consists of multiple organizations. In some instances, we may share your PII between organizations within McGraw-Hill Education to provide, maintain, and improve our products and services.
  6. Customers – As we are a service provider to your school, we may share your date with approved individuals at your school, such as administrators
  7. Law Enforcement – In the event that McGraw-Hill Education receives a legal demand for PII from a law enforcement agency, the request will only be honored if:
    1. The request complies with all laws and clearly establishes the legal need for disclosure.
    2. The request is related to a specific investigation and specific user accounts are implicated in that investigation.
    3. Whenever legally permissible, users shall receive notice that their information is being requested.

* * *

**_What privacy controls and choices do we offer you?_**

 ** _You may contact customer service to review or correct your PII._**

  1. Reviewing & correcting your information – We strive to ensure that the PII we have about you is accurate and current. However, since McGraw-Hill Education is a service provider to your school, please contact the appropriate contact at your school if you want to review your account information, or believe that the PII we have about you is inaccurate.
  2. Consent – As noted above, your educational institution is ultimately responsible for the privacy of your PII. MHE obtains consent from your institution to collect, process, and store your PII. If you have any questions regarding the collection and use of your PII, please contact the appropriate individual at your educational institution.

* * *

**_How do we protect your PII?_**

 ** _Our IT security team has established reasonable security measures to protect your PII._**

We use reasonable security measures to protect your PII from unauthorized access and use. 

* * *

**_Can you delete your PII?_**

 ** _You may request that we delete your PII through your school, however you should be aware this may limit your ability to use our products or services._**

We can delete your information at the request of your school. Since your school has hired us to manage this information for them, we ask that you or your parent make any request directly to your school. Please know that if we do receive a request to delete your information, you may no longer be able to access or use the digital learning solution. 

* * *

**_When do we store, transfer or process PII internationally?_**

 ** _McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization based in the U.S. Depending on your location, we may transfer and store your PII for processing in the U.S._**

McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization headquartered in the United States. Depending on your location and the product or service, your information may be stored and processed within secure data centers in the U.S., where U.S. law applies. If your data is stored locally, then your local laws prevail. 

We recognize and acknowledge current data protection laws in the European Union, Switzerland, and around the world. We follow the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Framework administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at http://www.export.gov/safeharbor. 

Any questions or complaints regarding this Policy or the collection, use, disclosure, or transfer of Personal Data covered by this Policy should be directed to [privacy@mheducation.com](mailto:privacy@mheducation.com). 

In the event your complaint cannot be resolved, you may contact the appropriate DPA or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner. The contact information for the EU DPAs is available at http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/index_en.htm. The contact information for the Commissioner is available at <http://www.edoeb.admin.ch/kontakt/index.html?lang=en>.

## Student Data Privacy Notice

### Introduction

As a global leader in providing digital learning systems for educators and students, McGraw-Hill Education is deeply committed to protecting the privacy of their customers and their students. Whether you are using Connect, ConnectEd, Engrade or any of our other solutions, we collect personal information that we use to provide, maintain and improve the solution. We are providing the below information so that you can understand how we protect and use your information. If you are under 18, we suggest that you review this information with your parents. Your school is ultimately responsible for your information, so we encourage you to reach out to your school if you have any questions or concerns about your privacy. Should the below information change, we will update it here, but more importantly, we will notify your school in writing and obtain their consent before implementing any new practices that affect your privacy beyond what is described. 

This information applies to all students who use our digital learning system. Educational institutions are best able to provide you with a full understanding of their privacy practices and more information on how their students' PII is collected, shared, and used. To obtain more detailed information about how PII is collected, used, and shared by or on behalf of an educational institution, please contact the appropriate individual at that institution. 

* * *

**_What is personally identifiable information (PII)?_**

 ** _Personally Identifiable Information, or PII, is information that can identify you, or when combined with other information can be used to identify you._**

Personally identifiable information, or PII, is information that can be used to identify you, such as your name, address, or ID numbers. PII also includes information that can be combined to identify you, such as your date of birth and birthplace. Any information that is combined with PII is also considered PII as long as it is linked to PII. For example, we couldn't identify you based on your grade level, however grade level is PII as long as it is connected to you. 

* * *

**_What PII do we collect and how do we use it?_**

 ** _We collect PII, such as contact information and education details, in order to provide you with the product and/or service requested._**

We only collect the information we require to provide, maintain and improve the digital learning solution you use. When you register, or are registered within one of our digital learning solutions, we typically only collect your name, school, instructor, class, and login information. However, once you begin using one of our solutions, we collect your input to questions, technical specifications, and other information about how you use the solution. As mentioned above, we use this information to provide you with the solution, as well as maintain and improve the solution. 

* * *

**_What other information do we collect?_**

 ** _We may also collect computer metadata and content to provide, improve, and maintain our products and services._**

When you use our digital learning systems, we collect information without you having to enter it through the use of cookies, web beacons or other tracking mechanisms. This includes information about your experience such as your IP address, operating systems, pages viewed, and time spent. This information is also used to enable the functions of the digital learning system, as well as customize, maintain, and improve our digital learning systems. You may disable cookies via your browser or third party mechanisms. However, some features of our digital learning systems may not functional properly without them. Third party cookies that may be used include Google Analytics and Webtrends. 

If you access our web sites from the European Union, you will be presented with an additional notification regarding cookies and will be provided with an opportunity to approve the use of cookies. 

You can change your Web browser's Internet preferences to disable or delete cookies, although that may affect certain functions on this site. To learn how to manage your cookies, please follow the instructions from your specific browser, or follow the links below: 

* * *

**_Do we use your PII to market to you?_**

 ** _We will not sell your PII or market to you using PII from our digital learning systems._**

We will not sell your PII to other organizations, nor will we send you advertisements using the information we collect while you use the solution. In addition, we will not share this information with any third party unless they are assisting us with providing, maintaining or improving the solution. If we do share your information, we only share it with those organizations that can commit to the same levels of privacy and security that we do. 

* * *

**_When do we share your PII with third parties?_**

 ** _In general, we only share your PII in order to provide, maintain, or improve our products or services, or respond to legal requests._**

  1. o-branded/Other Web Sites and Features – We may share your PII with third-party business partners for the purpose of providing the Service to you. Those business partners will be given limited access to the PII that is reasonably necessary to deliver the Service, and we will require that such third parties follow the same privacy and security practices as McGraw-Hill Education.
  2. Business Transfer – In the event of a sale, merger or acquisition, we may transfer your PII to a separate entity. This entity will be responsible for ensuring that your PII is used only for authorized purposes and by authorized persons in a manner consistent with the choices customers and prospects have made under this Policy, and that security, integrity and privacy of the information is maintained.
  3. Agents/Service providers – Sometimes we hire other companies to perform certain business-related functions for us. In certain instances, we provide these companies with access to your PII in order for them to perform their functions. However, we limit that access to only information required to perform their specific function, and we contractually require that these organizations follow the same privacy and security requirements.
  4. Affiliates – McGraw-Hill Education is a global corporation that consists of multiple organizations. In some instances, we may share your PII between organizations within McGraw-Hill Education to provide, maintain, and improve our products and services.
  5. Customers – As we are a service provider to your school, we may share your date with approved individuals at your school, such as administrators or educators
  6. Law Enforcement – In the event that McGraw-Hill Education receives a legal demand for customer data from a law enforcement agency that requests will only be honored if:
    1. The request complies with all laws and clearly establishes the legal need for disclosure.
    2. The request is related to a specific investigation and specific user accounts are implicated in that investigation.
    3. Whenever legally permissible, users shall receive notice that their information is being requested.

* * *

**_What privacy controls and choices do we offer you?_**

 ** _You may contact customer service to review or correct your PII._**

  1. Reviewing & correcting your information – We strive to ensure that the PII we have about you is accurate and current. However, since McGraw-Hill Education is a service provider to your school, please contact the appropriate contact at your school if you want to review your account information, or believe that the PII we have about you is inaccurate.
  2. Consent – As noted above, your educational institution is ultimately responsible for the privacy of your PII. MHE obtains consent from your institution to collect, process, and store your PII. If you have any questions regarding the collection and use of your PII, please contact the appropriate individual at your educational institution.

* * *

**_How do we protect your PII?_**

 ** _Our IT security team has established reasonable security measures to protect your PII._**

We use reasonable security measures to protect your PII from unauthorized access and use. 

* * *

**_Can you delete your PII?_**

 ** _You may request that we delete your PII through your school, however you should be aware this may limit your ability to use our products or services._**

We can delete your information at the request of your school. Since your school has hired us to manage this information for them, we ask that you or your parent make any request directly to your school. Please know that if we do receive a request to delete your information, you may no longer be able to access or use the digital learning solution. 

* * *

**_When do we store, transfer or process PII internationally?_**

 ** _McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization based in the U.S. Depending on your location, we may transfer and store your PII for processing in the U.S._**

McGraw-Hill Education is a global organization headquartered in the United States. Depending on your location and the product or service, your information may be stored and processed within secure data centers in the U.S., where U.S. law applies. If your data is stored locally, then your local laws prevail. 

We recognize and acknowledge current data protection laws in the European Union, Switzerland, and around the world. We follow the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Framework administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at http://www.export.gov/safeharbor. 

Any questions or complaints regarding this Policy or the collection, use, disclosure, or transfer of Personal Data covered by this Policy should be directed to [privacy@mheducation.com](mailto:privacy@mheducation.com). 

In the event your complaint cannot be resolved, you may contact the appropriate DPA or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner. The contact information for the EU DPAs is available at http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/index_en.htm. The contact information for the Commissioner is available at <http://www.edoeb.admin.ch/kontakt/index.html?lang=en>.
